Guide to the Richard Heyman Papers, 1983-1989.
Heyman, Richard papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Richard Heyman Papers, 1983-1989.
7770
June Keith
4.4 cubic feet.
Memorabilia, Photographs, Printed Materials, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scrapbooks, campaign material, speeches, photographs, political buttons, and other material chronicling Heyman's political career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
In 1983, Richard A. Heyman (1935-1994) was elected mayor of Key West, Florida, and became the first openly gay mayor in the United States. He moved to Key West in 1973 and opened Gingerbread Square Art Gallery. Heyman is best remembered for his work winning a second city-wide referendum that lead to Key West's first wastewater treatment facility.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scrapbooks, campaign material, speeches, photographs, political buttons, and other material chronicling Heyman's political career, including a copy of John Mikytuck's documentary about Heyman and the early AIDS crisis in Key West, "The Newcomer."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Keith, June; Illchuk, Peter,
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease)--Florida.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Scrapbook made by June Keith and Richard Heyman, November 1983-June 1985 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook made by June Keith and Richard Heyman, July 1985-October 1987 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook made by June Keith and Richard Heyman, October 1985-June 1989 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook made by June Keith and Richard Heyman, March 1989-November 1989 (Box 3)
- Political Memories 1979-1985, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ethics Issues, 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- City Commissioner Campaign materials, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- City Commissioner Campaign Money and Expenses, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- City Commissioner Campaign Mass Mailings, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Voting Information, October - November 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- City Commissioner Campaign Public Events, Outreach, Radio, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Campaign Commissioner Campaign Contributions and Workers List, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Absentee Voter Thank You Letter, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Victory Party Poster, November 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Treasurer's Receipts, etc., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Commissioner Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1981 Charter Revision Committee papers, February-June 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Charter Revision Outreach, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Mayor Campaign, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Campaign 1983, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15a)
- Mayor Campaign Publicity, Public Outreach, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 1983 Fundraising, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Mayor Campaign Information on Polling Booths, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Address Sheets, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Key West Code Enforcement Board, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Sewer Management, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Bahama Village, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Tennessee Williams Fine Arts Center, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Peter Ilchuck Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Mayor Heyman Correspondence, 1984, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Incident Report 6/11/84, June 6, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Heyman Farewell Address, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Supervisor of Elections License Plate, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Senate Bills and Miscellaneous Documents, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Peter Ilchuck's Files, 1975-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Speeches Written By Peter Ilchuck, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Campaign Photos, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Letter from President Reagan, November 1, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Photos from Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Clipping Mailed to Heyman, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Wesley Calvin's Clippings, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Heyman Press Clippings, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 37-39)
- Peter Ilchuck Political Buttons, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 40-43)
- Mayor Reports, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Special Reports, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Short Subjects, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Political Issues, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 47)
- C2000/Focus 1990 Report, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Heyman Defends Public Nudity Newspaper Clipping, October 27, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- "This is a Free Ticket", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Peter Ilchuck US House of Representatives ID, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Peter Ilchuck Photo Album Scrapbook, October 1985 - May 1989 (Box 5)
- Peter Ilchuck Supervisor of Elections Scrapbook, 1986 - 1989 (Box 5)
- Contribution Cards, ca. 1983 (Box 6)
- Peter Ilchuck (13:60s), n.d. (Box 6, Folder tr8737a)
- AIDS/HIV Florida Keys Update - Produced by Joe Dietrich, 1993 (Box 6, Folder DVD-671)
- The Newcomer Documentary by John Mikytuck, n.d. (Box 6, Folder DVD-672)
- Richard Heyman Campaign Radio Advertisements, n.d. (Box 7, Folder tr8738 - tr8748)
- Mayor Returns Montage - Last Meet, n.d. (Box 7, Folder V-5516)
- Highlights of the Political Career of Richard A. Heyman as Mayor and Commissioner - Taped by TCI Ch. 5, Key West, FL. - Edited by Joe Dietrich, n.d. (Box 7, Folder V-5517)
- "Keynotes" with Mayor Richard Heyman - Saturday Night Live Highlights, April 25, 1984 (Box 7, Folder V-5518)
- Nightwatch Interviews Mayor Richard Heyman, n.d. (Box 7, Folder V-5519)
- Heyman, Ilchuck Clippings, 1979-1991 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
- John Mikytuck "The Newcomer" Documentary materials, n.d. (Map-case DD-23, Folder 1)